<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rashi</title>
    <description>Free Soul</description>
    <link>http://soulfulmind.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://soulfulmind.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 01:48:09 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 01:48:09 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Being In Love Is Stranger Than Falling In Love!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/being-in-love.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isn’t being in love one of the strangest relationships? We all have our own personalize definition of what it really mean to us. Why is it so? Why there is no common defined statement that explains what actually love is and what it has in store for us if we proceed! It seems the answer to the most sought and yes, the silliest of the questions lies in the fact that ‘It’s all in our mind’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No two human beings think on the same track. Everyone has own thought process and needs. Every person desires different things from life. And to get that balance we sought another soul to fill the gaps. But do we remain intact in the process we started? Most of us do not!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason being that while searching for the love we do remember the balancing process but after being in love, we unknowingly target our mirror image in our loved one. Everything that they do irritates us, as we believe that it is not the way to do certain things. But if we think another way around, if they behave in a manner we want them to then how they will be an altogether a different being! We just want to twist them to fit our own image mould. But while doing so we forget that we are actually trying to see our reflection in them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love is certainly not searching your own reflection but about seeing the other person as they are and loving them for it. Let them be free to be perfect in their own ways. In a simple way to understand this complicated version of love, it can be said that you may consider receiving a bunch of roses or hearing words like ‘forever’ as a gratitude for love but for your better half, the gesture of even peeling a fruit for you just because you don’t like doing it, may be a gesture of love! It’s all in our minds and our beliefs. Love cannot be measured by keeping the count of materialistic things, but it is measured by the actions of your loved one. Love is not always in complicated gestures; it is also in many small uncountable things that we usually forget to notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that doesn’t mean you cannot contribute anything new to your relationship because love means acceptance! Again, every relationship has its own set of rules to live by and so they are flexible! The only catch here is never to forget while proposing a new rule that the thing you are talking about is not only absorbed with other’s mind but with their heart as well. Instead of being a critic, being an encourager helps. And not to forget that most of the ideas in any relationship are rejected because of the unsympathetic tone of voice. Compliments are the catalyst for people but the greatest compliment that you can give to a person you love is your undivided attention and your eagerness to listen what they feel. It is the easiest as well the rare gift we ever give to our loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make your own rules for your relationship, as there are no generalize definitions that exist but the personalized ones that define you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 11:17:52 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://soulfulmind.github.io/blog/2017/being-in-love/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://soulfulmind.github.io/blog/2017/being-in-love/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hope,</category>
        
        <category>motivation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let’s keep up our hopes!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hope.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this journey of life, dreams and hope are the catalysts. They keep us moving ahead and to look forward to each new day as a new beginning. Instead of always looking how far we have to go; enjoying every moment where we are, is what life is all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone should dream! Dreams give us hope. The moment we stop dreaming, it’s like accepting that your fate can never change. Hope is not about proving anything! It’s about believing in a thing and to follow it. It’s somewhat like choosing love over hatred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopes, dreams and believing in yourself doesn’t count much when it’s easy to believe in yourself or when things are in your favor and future looks bright. These things really counts when you can see darkness and no way out. It counts when you feel now nothing can be done. When you feel it’s the end! That’s when hope and believing in you really matters. Hope remind us in these darkest phases of our life that every truth will shine above false, that every failure is a step towards success and that every try is a lesson we are learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everybody has their own inner circle that consists of people who are their home team. These are the people whom you call when something terrible happens. They always know everything that’s going wrong with you whether they are far or near. They are the people who care for you, share secrets and cry when you cry. No matter what, no matter where…these people are your strength. But there are also the other set of people out of this inner circle. These are the people who reject you and make you feel less. Envy you and what not! But this is the time when you have to believe in yourself and remind yourself that someone rejecting you doesn’t mean that you should reject yourself or feel any less. Although sometimes it hurts when a person rejects you as that person’s opinion means world to you! That is the time when believing in you really counts. That is the time to believe, to hope and to dream that again you will find your way. Things will be fine. That one day you will feel you are truly blessed above all odds.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 11:14:52 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://soulfulmind.github.io/blog/2017/hopes-up/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://soulfulmind.github.io/blog/2017/hopes-up/</guid>
        
        
        <category>hope,</category>
        
        <category>motivation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Self Encouragement: Be your own motivator!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/encourage.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is a series of ups and downs. When a person is in the life curve going up, then there are many people who are there for him/her. But the real scenario comes in the forefront when the life curve is going down. This is the time when a support is required, be it mental or emotional support. If a person is lucky enough to be surrounded by people who are excellent supporters and motivators, the down curve doesn’t seem much difficult. But what if you are not that lucky? Will you give up? The answer lies within! It is ‘Self encouragement’!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self encouragement is not only a virtue to follow in tough times. Many times we are seeking someone to celebrate our successes too! Why is it needed at all? Having well wishers is always a plus but if there is no one then do you not deserve a celebration of your success? Yes you do! When there is no one to compliment you, then you should compliment yourself. Celebrate your success with yourself! Encouragement does not always come from other people. It also comes from within!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self love is the key for self encouragement. You deserve your love as much as anyone else! When we love ourselves, there is never a need to justify ourselves or other people about why we sleep late, why we take vacations, why we shop, why we indulge in eating or why we keep on spoiling ourselves every now and then! Self love is being comfortable doing things that brings beauty and adds quality to our life. If we will love ourselves, we will not rely on others for our happiness or look up to others to make us realize our worth. Loving self and realizing self worth is the pathway for self encouragement. When we believe in our capability, encouragement comes automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever you will take a new path in life, there will be people telling you that you are wrong. Many difficulties will arise that will convince you to believe these people who criticize you. But you have to be strong and believe in you. You are the only source of encouraging yourself at these difficult times. We have to remember that the people who seek most approvals are the ones who get the least and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In life, everything cannot be perfect for you to take a new course of action! There will always be some challenges, few obstacles and conditions that are unfavorable for you. Despite of all these, along with encouraging yourself, take a step ahead! The moment you start taking steps, you will feel that you are growing stronger and stronger, more confident and more successful! It is always tough to take first steps and self encouragement acts as a catalyst to take these steps!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 07:46:52 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://soulfulmind.github.io/blog/2017/encourage/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://soulfulmind.github.io/blog/2017/encourage/</guid>
        
        
        <category>encouragement,</category>
        
        <category>motivation</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
